<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Amar Tabakovic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Amar Tabakovic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>us-en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 01:13:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 23:36:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/uses/</guid>
      <description>List of things I use on a regular basis.
Editor and Terminal  Visual Studio Code with Vim plugin installed as my main editor IntelliJ IDEA for anything Java related Visual Studio for anything C# related zsh iTerm2 Homebrew for installing tools and software git  Software  GitHub for storing and versioning my source code Adobe XD for designing mockups Insomnia as an API client DBngin for locally running database instances DBeaver as a database management client Google Chrome as my primary browser Spotify for listening to music  Workstation  2020 MacBook Air (13-inch) 2x Dell P2720D (27-inch, 1440p) Ducky One 2 Mini (red switches) Logitech MX Master 3  Code C#/ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon for code screenshots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/carbon-for-code-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 13:26:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/carbon-for-code-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Create and share beautiful images of your source code. Start typing or drop a file into the text area to get started.
 Carbon is a web-based code snippet generator, which you can use to create screenshots of your source code. Carbon supports syntax highlighting for over 60 languages and is highly customizable.
Compared to creating a screenshot of the code editor or copying the code and pasting it into a Word OpenDocument object, this is much easier and aesthetically more pleasant (atleast in my opinion).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark mode in Hugo with SCSS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hugo-dark-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 22:17:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hugo-dark-theme/</guid>
      <description>Not too long ago, I developed my personal website using the static site generator Hugo. While coming up with designs for this website, I was plagued with the choice of implementing it in either a light theme or a dark theme. I liked both variants, so I was very indecisive until I came up with an idea:
To implement both variants using a light/dark mode toggler.
And so I did using HTML, SCSS and plain JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>amartabakovic.ch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/amartabakovic-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 22:14:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/amartabakovic-ch/</guid>
      <description>For a while now, I wanted to create a personal website. I originally envisioned to develop it in plain HTML and CSS, then in Webpack and JS, afterwards in Vue.js and now I&amp;rsquo;ve decided once and for all to use something called Hugo.
 Tech The website is mainly powered by the static site generator Hugo, which compiles markdown into HTML files. Hugo allows for fast compilation times and lightweight websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 15:11:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>At this point in time I have no idea what to write about. I&amp;rsquo;ll see what comes out of it.
 The wise man seeks little joys, knowing that life is long and that his quota of great joys is distinctly limited.
 - William Feather</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 23:20:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Amar. I&amp;rsquo;m 19 years old and from Basel, Switzerland.
I am currently completing an IT internship as part of my education at IMS Basel.
In my free time, I like to play the bass and guitar. Additionally, I have a keen interest in watches, vinyl and mechanical keyboards.
What I use.
Disclaimer: Views expressed here are not supported by any university, company or organization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
